# **ANUBHUTI JAIN**

255 King Street, San Francisco, CA | 206.556.8464 | anubhutijain111@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/anubhutijain/

### **PROFILE**

**8+ years** of design experience solving nuanced customer facing problems in ecommerce, financial and experimentation domain.

Experience solving for global usecases and problems. Worked in consumer as well as enterprise/business workspace across multiple platforms.

Have successfully shipped products, created design systems, managed ICs and brought business impact through product thinking.

#### **EDUCATION**

CARNEGIE MELLON UNIVERSITY (Masters in Human Computer Interaction - MHCI) Class of 2011, Pittsburgh, PA

DHIRUBHAI AMBANI INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION & COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGY (B.Tech, ICT)
Class of 2010, Gandhinagar, INDIA

### SKILLS

**HCI** Methods

Affinity Diagram, Card Sorting, Cognitive Walkthroughs, Contextual Inquiry and Design, Cultural Probes (Diary Studies), Guerrilla Interviews, Heuristic Evaluation, Think Alouds, Personas and Scenarios, Storyboarding, User Workflows and Journeys, Wireframing, Visual Specs, Ul Guidelines, Design Workshops

#### **TOOLS**

Axure, Keynote, Sketch, Abstarct, Illustrator, Indesign, Photoshop, Zepplin, Pixate, Invision

## **INTERESTS**

Avid traveler and experience seeker, Sports & fitness enthusiast, Certified Scuba Diver, Sketching, Photography, Creative Writing

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# NETFLIX | Senior Product Designer, Experimentation Platform Los Gatos, United States Oct 2018 - Present

- Lead designer working on Quasi testing tool in the Experimentation Platform
- Worked on understanding the cross team workflows to identify needs and inform which direction product should invest in.
- Defined a framework for conflict management while setting up tests to avoid dilution of test effects thereby enabling stronger findings which can be production-ized
- Created a design component library to standardize UX across all experimentation tools

# **AMAZON | User Experience Designer, Seller Experience** *Seattle, United States*

Feb 2017 - Sep 2018

- Lead designer working on portfolio of products and tools to enable sellers to expand, list and price their products in multiple marketplaces effectively(\$6bn+GMS).
  - Key initiatives include a tool for sellers to quickly replicate their listings across multiple marketplaces, pricing rules that enable sellers to manage their pricing effectively and enabling sellers to learn and launch in a new marketplacs
- Owner for defining seller experience and vision for inbounding products into Amazon warehouse.

# FLIPKART | Lead User Experience Designer, Seller and Consumer Aug 2014 - Aug 2016 Bengaluru, India

- Owner of Flipkart Seller Design's Team UX
- Created and implemented seamless processes between design, product and technology
- Defined and executed component library and interaction patterns for web and mobile
- · Lead Designer on Flipkart Seller Mobile App
- Core Designer on Flipkart Ping(Social Shopping)
- Fostered user empathy and defined a research process integrated with iterative design

# GROUPON | Design Research and Strategist, Consumer UX

Palo Alto, United States

- Fostered user empathy and defined a research process integrated with iterative design
- Led usability research as well as in depth user research for new features and understanding user base for multiple projects
  - Created user personas to foster empathy and impact product roadmaps.
  - Documented Groupon Customer Journey Map to identify breakdowns in the customer acquisition process and help prioritize feature fixes
  - · Led the research component of Groupon's mobile redesign project
- Initiated and conceptualized redesign to consolidate UX for redemption of multiple channels of Groupon. Collaborated with customer support team to understand issues with the process.

### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

## IxDA Seattle | Board member

Dec 2017 - Present

Nov 2011 - Aug 2014

Seattle, United States

• Manage volunteer coordination efforts, community engagement and strategy.

### Interation 19 | Volunteer Committee

Oct 2018 - Feb 2019

Seattle, United States

• As part of the organizing team, I was responsible for planning volunteer needs pre and during the conference. The tasks included onboarding volunteers, communication, defining roles and responsibilities, managing tasks during the conference